# Diego Vidal Lopez

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | X | Wellfound | Medium | Portfolio | +52 993 432 0592 | Villahermosa, Tab, MX. 86190

## **SUMMARY**

Curiosity-driven Full-Stack Developer and a fast learner who went from Customer Service to software development in 9 months adopting a Growth Mindset on the way. I bring mentoring, adaptability, quick learning, and 2+ years of experience working with technologies like Node, JavaScript, React, and Ruby on Rails. Open to Full-Stack roles in dynamic tech environments, be it at big companies, or startups.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind-CSS.

Back-End: Node, Javascript, Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL.

**Tools & Methods**: Git, GitHub, Vite, Webpack, RSpec, Jest, Postman, Render, Heroku, Chrome Dev Tools, Mobile First, Responsive Development, Gitflow, TDD, MVC, REST APIs, Linux.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Code review, Time Management, Cross-cultural.

### **EXPERIENCE**

OUTLIER Remote

# Al Trainer Generalist (Contractor)

Jun 2023 - Present

Evaluate AI-generated responses based on factual accuracy, safety, and adherence to instructions. Analyze prompts and assess the quality of AI outputs and Provide actionable feedback to enhance AI models' reliability.

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

#### Full Stack Web Developer

Apr 2023 - Present

<u>Book a Concert</u> — This project consists of a Single Page Application (SPA) and an API that allows users to book concerts or create independent events for others to book. Users can register, reserve, or create concerts.

• Built with: (HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails and PostgreSQL).

<u>Budget App</u> — Server Side Rendering Application (SSR) following Model View Controller architecture, that allows users to manage their budget. Users can create an account, add transactions, and create new categories.

• Built with: (HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind-CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL).

MICROVERSE Remote

#### Mentor (Volunteer)

Apr 2023 - Nov 2023

- Supported 8 developers with React and Rails app deployment from branches using Render and Github pages and helped to solve assets pipeline issues.
- Guided 5 developers with Git, Gitflow, and merge conflicts providing constructive feedback.

TELEPERFORMANCE

#### **Bilingual Customer Service Agent**

Remote Apr 2022 – Jan 2023

- Supported 6 different brands in less than 6 months demonstrating quick learning skills.
- Resolved unique problems for B2B and B2C clients in hundreds of interactions, maintaining a 98% customer satisfaction rating.

# **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Apr 2023 - Nov 2023

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Completed 40 projects (solo and as part of a team) with JavaScript, React, Redux Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL while mastering algorithms and data structures. Some of them were Recipe App, Budget App, and Book a Concert.
- Performed code reviews and remote pair programming using GitHub, and industry-standard git-flow, attended
  daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers gaining teamwork
  experience.

FREECODECAMP Apr 2021 – Jun 2021

#### **Responsive Web Design**

Spent 300 hours of coursework learning HTML5 and CSS3; built 5 short projects (<u>Survey</u>, <u>Tribute Page</u>, <u>Technical Documentation Page</u>, and <u>Landing Page</u>) gaining a better understanding of responsive mobile-friendly design.